<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Vegan Bingo</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_show_screen">Vegan Bingo</string>
    <string name="screen_heading">Choice icon</string>
    <string name="bacon_description">Just saying Bacon/Steak etc.</string>
    <string name="bacon_main">This can occur in any number of places, on a social thread, in a conversation about food, over dinner etc.\nIn Internet terms this is called a Troll, someone deliberately saying some offensive because they think they are being clever, despite the fact it has little more intelligence or humour in it other than being offensive.\nIn deeper terms this is called a cold joke, trying to paint something as humourous to themselves in order to avoid dealing with the psychological ramifications of the immoral action they are participating in.\nOn some level they know what they are doing is wrong and they are doing what they can to push it away.</string>
    <string name="hitler_description">Hitler was a vegetarian</string>
    <string name="hitler_main">Hitler, Pol Pot etc, often trudged out as examples of&#8230;well it is hard to say.  Really what it is about is the person trying to maintain their own sense of moral righteousness by slanderously associating you with some of the most evil people in history.\nThis is of course motivated by the fact that they know they are participating in something immoral, and rather than taking any action to stop this, are using anything they can grab on to to drag other people down to their level.\nHitler, Pol Pot, neither were ethical vegetarians, they did so for short periods due to health problems and Hitler certainly would rather be eating his favourite sausages.  The Nazis did enact some laws against animal cruelty, they also had the Winter Relief programme helping poor people during the cold months and anti smoking campaigns, so not everything they did was evil.</string>
    <string name="protein_description">Where do you get your protein?</string>
    <string name="protein_main">Where did people get their obsession with asking about protein?  Meat and dairy industry propaganda which reaches far more people than any unbiased nutritional advice.\nThere has never been any study which has shown protein deficiency in people following a plant based diet.  Protein deficiency is unknown in any population who eats enough calories, regardless of what their diet is.  There may be some edge cases, but vegetarianism and veganism are not one of them.\nHow much protein do you need? You weight in kilograms times 0.8 to 1.8 depending on how much weight bearing or endurance exercise you do.</string>
    <string name="cheese_description">I could never give up cheese</string>
    <string name="cheese_main">Of course the second part of this statement might be "No matter how much cruelty is involved".\nHopefully this is simply untrue, that instead people can be motivated by rational and ethical concerns.  If people understood that it wasn\'t a particularly healthy thing to eat, contributes to the veal trade in young calves, is environmentally polluting and unhealthy for the cows themselves, hopefully they could find the motivation to remove just one of the hundreds or thousands of ingredients in their diet.</string>
    <string name="cow_description">What would happen to all the cows?</string>
    <string name="cow_main">Cows are not allowed to breed naturally, the idea that they are has more to do with romanatic visions of the countryside than intensive industrial farming.\nTheir breeding is strictly controlled by the farmers and companies engineering their bodies for human purposes. The population of livestock rises and falls quickly in relation to human demand.\nSadly for livestock however it is unlikely that a change will happen overnight, it will probably be gradual so carnists can stop losing sleep over the terrible notion of these creatures we have brought into being living out their natural livespans.</string>
    <string name="plants_description">Don\'t plants have feelings?</string>
    <string name="plants_main">Sadly people who ask this are likely to care even less about plants than they do non human animals.\nThere is a serious point here, something which would generally elude anyone silly enough to phrase the question this way, and that is where do we draw the line of compassion towards other life which shares a common evolutionary heritage.\nWe could discuss levels of self awareness, the ability to suffer, the presence of a central nervous system, in all of which science of course should be our guide.\nIf we err in our understanding however let it be on the side of compassion.</string>
    <string name="teeth_description">What about our canine teeth?</string>
    <string name="teeth_main">Human canine teeth look rather lame compared with the ones sported by our cousins the gorillas, who are either wholly vegan or some eat small insects.  Indeed all primates have canine teeth, primarily used for dominance displays and as weapons.\nIt is unfortunate that the name canine has caused so much confusion, however the presence of them provides no justification for cruelty, in either using them to tear the flesh of innocent animals, or rivals for resources from our own species.\nIn any case it is our conscience, not our biology, that should be guiding our actions.</string>
    <string name="humane_description">What if we raised animals more humanely?</string>
    <string name="humane_main">A lot of people talk about humane farming, but there is precious little evidence that anyone is at all rigorous about doing it or supporting it with their money.\nSome people do try to buy more humane animal products at home, but care little once they leave the house.  Also the pure economics of the livestock industries mean inhumanity is inevitable.  Evidence of this is how some countries have taken the enlightened step to ban caged hens however this has been followed by a loosening of cruelty standards on free range for economic reasons.\nTo feed billions of people animal products at every meal, is always going to take an industrial system, a long way removed from the image of the country farm many people have in their minds.</string>
    <string name="food_description">Why do vegans eat things resembling animal products?</string>
    <string name="food_main">For a start, most animal products do not look like animal products.  Cheese, sausages, fish fingers, they are creations for a culinary purpose.\nMany vegans avoid products resembling animal foods, however others find them a convenient and less cruel alternative.\nIt is not an ingredient that we are against, it is the suffering and murder.  Remove those aspects, as vegan products strive to do, and there is no reason not to enjoy whatever pleases you.</string>
    <string name="natural_description">Meat eating is natural/has always been done</string>
    <string name="natural_main">As much as humans wish for a moral universe, nature is obviously amoral.  Good things, terrible things, all happen governed by elegant but soulless mathematical laws.\nTo say then that something is natural and that this is alone needed as a moral defense of the action, would be to ignore the vast number of terrible things that go on in nature.\nMost of the highest points of human civilisation involve going beyond nature, law, justice, democracy, modern medicine, philosophy, and perhaps the highest of all is the study of ethics.\nFinally to call the modern factory farming system natural, is to render the word meaningless.  Animals in nature are free.</string>
    <string name="eat_description">What can you eat?</string>
    <string name="eat_main">Ask anyone who enjoys cooking who has become vegan, and they will tell you a world of ingredients they had never used before opened up to them.  Many people rediscover a love of food, and use the process of becoming vegan to eat a healthier diet.  Add to this that 90% of any healthy diet is already vegan, and the other 10% we replace with nuts, seeds, beans, legumes, grains, tofu, tempeh, seitan and the ever widening variety of "mock" products, as well as the plethora of different plant based milks, soy, almond, oat, rice, hemp, quinoa, coconut and so on.\nReally you are just replacing a handful of the hundreds or even thousands of ingredients in your diet with non animal based ones.  It is not hard, as much as you might prefer to think it is.</string>
    <string name="notmuch_description">I don\'t each much meat</string>
    <string name="notmuch_main">This is a positive and healthy statement, but we soon realise when we spend time with people who assert this that they eat meat at almost every meal.\nOur ideas of what a normal diet is are culturally shaped.  The fact that someone eats less meat than their unhealthy friend, or chooses fish or chicken instead of red meat, does not equate to not eating much meat.\nThe average person eats twice as much meat per portion as is recommended by nutritionists, and many countries are eating meat many times what they were only a few decades ago.\nIf you have more days vegetarian than otherwise, you can probably claim to be not eating much meat, otherwise you are probably eating more than you should.\nFor the animals who will live lives in factory farms for your meal, that amount would obviously be zero.</string>
    <string name="what_description">What about people?</string>
    <string name="what_main">The premise of this statement is that whilst there is human suffering, we shouldn\'t worry about the suffering of other animals.  Vegans don\'t believe that such a choice needs to be made and are concerned about the suffering of all animals, humans included.\nIndeed they are often related, environmental care affects all that share the earth, teaching compassion helps all that can suffer, switching to a plant based diet is going to allow more food to be grown with less land.\nThe idea that humans are in a different sphere to all other animals is a pre darwinian conception of ourselves.  All who can suffer deserve our consideration, especially those who suffer as a direct consequence of our own actions.</string>
    <string name="cant_description">Oh, you can\'t eat that</string>
    <string name="cant_main">It is interesting that people frame our refraining from animal products with the word "can\'t" as if it is involuntary, rather than "won\'t" which reflects a choice.\nVegans can eat whatever they want, they make a conscious choice not to eat certain products out of concern for the animals involved.</string>
    <string name="aspirational_description">I\'d like to be vegan, but&#8230;</string>
    <string name="aspirational_main">The more mainstram veganism becomes, the more people are convinced by our reasons for living vegan, we more we hear this.  It\'s a sign that veganism has arrived.\nOf course as vegans we know it\'s pretty easy to be vegan in places where food isn\'t scarce.  Why people don\'t take that step has more to do with habit and conformity than anything else.\nSo what you should do here is clear, help them achieve an aspiration for themselves.  Start by showing them all the resources online that are free to help them, any local shops or restaurants good for vegan products, and of course the best propaganda which is feeding them great vegan food.</string>
    <string name="preachy_description">Vegans are preachy/each to their own</string>
    <string name="preachy_main">OK there are preachy vegans who need to chill out.  Any carnist who has had bad experiences with preachy vegans, should try being vegan for a while and seeing how much the reverse is also true (hence this phone app).\nThis comes down to people\'s idea of what life is all about, some think it is just about being popular, conforming and they can\'t understand people who would expend their social capital advocating their beliefs.  They might even express this point of view in cliches such as "to each their own", or "live and let live".  To some degree that should be respected, getting upset with someone is unlikely to change their point of view and will probably be counterproductive.  On another level however the animals can\'t speak for themselves, so we have to do it.  Therefore we need to not be overbearing, but make sure out points are heard.\nOne of the best forms of advocacy is being a strong and positive example of veganism.</string>

</resources>